Hi, in this lesson, you will learn about the top completion and navigation features in
Google Integrity.
This is one of most powerful features that helps you code faster by predicting what you want
to write next and helping you move around your code efficiently.
So top navigation in ei-powered features that works as you type.
As you will see, if I will type, for example, get, yeah, it already suggests me trying to
predict what I'd like to do, yeah, because this is kind of intelligent assistance that
watches what you're doing and suggesting the next logical step.
It can analyze your code, understand the context of what you're building, because we have
the file name as a calendar, we have the calendar class name.
So here already know, we're building calendar.
And based on it, he can suggest the next step.
So, instead of typing everything manually, you cannot set suggestions with a simple
top press.
For example, if I like this suggestion, I really want to add get_mounds and get_your_of_functions,
I can just click top, and these suggestions will be accepted.
Also, the next powerful feature is top to jump, as you see, here is a top to jump, text,
what it does, yeah.
This is where the navigation comes, yeah?
After you accept a code suggestion, top can predict where you need to edit next, yeah?
Maybe you created the function, and you need to close this function somewhere later in
place, yeah?
The top to text is the spotter than offers to jump your cursor directed to set location,
where you need to do something with that function, yeah?
You don't need to scroll a search manually.
Just press top key, again, and your cursor teleports to the next logical spot.
So this works both with the same file, and also across the different files.
So you will see, if I click top, Microsoft was moved, I click top, okay, yeah.
Sometimes it's a bit slow, you need some time to do the next suggestion, yeah, but as you
see, I have suggestions that I can use this, get_mounds, yeah.
For example, let me click top, yeah, and click top to get here, and I see, I finished.
Then I can top to jump, I click, uh, what next, I click top, that must happen, yeah.
Sometimes it, uh, if you don't have enough context in your file, it may be a bit stupid,
yeah, but if you have a big file, and I clearly understand what you are next step, yeah,
then it will be more powerful, and more, you can give you more precise suggestions, yeah.
Uh, imagine I'd like to add a new method, yeah, I just go to the new line, and it suggests
me get_moundsname, yeah.
And right here, you might see a few suggestions from AI, like if you implemented some function,
it may show you some different variations how this function can be implemented, yeah.
And you can, uh, move between them, yeah, or just click right in, um, left keys, so you
can click accept, you can accept word by word if you press common, and right, yeah, or if
you use in Windows, you can use control plus right key, and you can accept it word with
words, and for example, I'd like to accept the method name, and for example, I'd like
to accept the method, but I'd like to send, for example, to the months, the n-n-n-n-nother,
param, yeah, and start accepting to the place I'd like to change, for example, I view
tie up short, and then I go top again, yeah.
And after I click to the top to jump, you see it immediately or replace it, the function
and get months to the get months name, yeah, imagine if it want to do it, yeah.
Okay, the next nice feature I'd like to show you, it's stopped to import, let's create
a new file, uh, call it helpers, of course, just, and let's export some function, um, get
months name, yeah, and right here I will remove the function, yeah, any mention, uh, so
it show us, so we still use and get months name, but this is, uh, not implemented in this
file, and if we click top to jump, uh, it suggests us to replace the implementation of
the function, yeah, because we get months name, we pass the months name, and then we can
click top to jump, and you see it's at an import, yeah, this is the next variation of this
feature of top to import, yeah, uh, when you reference a function or class variable from
another file, I take gravity that tags that, and if it's not imported yet, instead of
manually scrolling to the top and typing this import by yourself, it did, it does everything
automatically for you, uh, it can also correct the import, if for example, you import in a
few, uh, few functions from one file, it can also extend it to add in another import,
so this work for JavaScript, for TypeScript, for Python, and many other languages, so it
keeps the workflow really smooth and eliminates the annoying back and forth of adding imports
manually, so let me also be explain you how it learns from your work, yeah, the more you
stop a navigation feature, the smarter it gets, it learn from your coding style, the
patterns you use, and the changes you accept or reject, yeah, if you continue the right
code in a certain way, anti gravity picks on as that and adjust its suggestions to match
your preference, this person-wise experience makes coding feel natural and keep your productive
without constant interruptions, so I will know, um, how to use, now you know and understand
how to use top and navigation features, you know, how to use top to jump, top to import
what's the difference, yeah, you can use it, you can start using it, uh, to write code
as faster of navigate the project more efficiently and let the eye handle some repetitive
parts of work, yeah, while focusing on, uh, building great features, okay, see you in the
next lesson.